<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming on 0x32++</title><link>https://blog.0x32.co.uk/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on 0x32++</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 10:05:23 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.0x32.co.uk/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Search from the command line</title><link>https://blog.0x32.co.uk/posts/searchit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 10:05:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.0x32.co.uk/posts/searchit/</guid><description>A simple Python script to allow you to quickly search from the command line that I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with on and off for a while.
https://github.com/alastairhm/searchit
It uses the Python Library Fire to automatically generate the command line interface which is something I stumbled across recently.
You either pass it a paramater for the search term or if one it not passed it used whatever is in your clipboard buffet.</description></item><item><title>Learn C on Linux</title><link>https://blog.0x32.co.uk/posts/learnc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 10:35:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.0x32.co.uk/posts/learnc/</guid><description>Came across this article of ways to Learn C on Linux which took me back to my 3rd real programming job.
It was with a software house mainly working with C/C++ on Linux/ Unix and embedded systems.
My first real experience use C/C++ in a professional environment, happy days with a good bunch of geeks.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve never tried it before it would be a good change from more recent languages to learn C for a challenge.</description></item><item><title>Learning Rust (again)</title><link>https://blog.0x32.co.uk/posts/rust001/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 14:10:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.0x32.co.uk/posts/rust001/</guid><description>Learning Rust New year, new programming language, decided to go and learn Rust programming.
Some interesting concepts so far.
Learn Rust Repo
Resources https://www.udemy.com/course/learning-rust/ https://www.rust-lang.org/</description></item><item><title>Processing</title><link>https://blog.0x32.co.uk/posts/processing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 09:55:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.0x32.co.uk/posts/processing/</guid><description>Make learning programming fun It is funny how things come around again, when I started learning to programming back in the 1980s on my 8 bit machines (ZX81, Acorn Electron, BBC Micro) I used to play with graphics a lot. It gave instant feedback and visually showed the results of things like recursion. I had great fun playing with Fractals and other procedural generated images.
Recently I discovered a YouTube channel and programming platform which took me right back to those days.</description></item></channel></rss>